I killed Sirius Black!
You coming to get me?
Harry, can you get me?
Harry?
Stupefy!
Harry!
Ginny!
Molly.
It's easy for them to get to you.
You're bloody lucky you weren't killed.
You have to realize who you are, Harry.
I know who I am, Hermione, all right?
Sorry.
Lav, come on. Of course I'll wear it.
That's my Won-Won.
Excuse me, I have to go and vomit.
I'd like to know
where you get your information.
More knowledgeable
than half the staff, you are.
Sir...
...is it true
that Professor Merrythought is retiring?
Now, Tom.
I couldn't tell you if I knew, could I?
By the way, thank you for the pineapple.
You're quite right, it is my favorite.
But how did you know?
Intuition.
Gracious. Is it that time already?
Off you go, boys, or Professor Dippet
will have us all in detention.
Look sharp, Tom. Don't want to be caught
out of bed after hours.
- Is something on your mind, Tom?
- Yes, sir.
You see, I couldn't think
of anyone else to go to.
The other professors,
well, they're not like you.
They might misunderstand.
Go on.
I was in the library the other night...
...in the Restricted Section...
...and I read something rather odd
about a bit of rare magic.
And I thought perhaps
you could illuminate me.
It's called, as I understand it...
I beg your pardon?
I don't know anything about such things,
and if I did, I wouldn't tell you!
Now, get out of here at once, and don't
let me ever catch you mentioning it again!
Confused?
I'd be surprised if you weren't.
Well, I don't understand.
What happened?
This is perhaps the most important
memory I've collected.
It is also a lie.
This memory has been tampered with...
...by the same person whose memory it is,
our old friend, Professor Slughorn.
But why would he tamper
with his own memory?
- I suspect he's ashamed of it.
- Why?
Why, indeed?
I asked you to get to know
Professor Slughorn, and you have done so.
Now I want you to persuade him
to divulge his true memory...
...any way you can.
I don't know him that well, sir.
This memory is everything.
Without it, we are blind.
Without it, we leave the fate
of our world to chance.
You have no choice.
You must not fail.
So I'd highly recommend
you reacquaint yourself...
...with the chapter on antidotes.
I'll tell you more about bezoars
in our next class. Right, off you go.
Alys, don't forget your rat tail.
Aha. If it isn't
the Prince of Potions himself.
To what do I owe this pleasure?
Sir, I wondered
if I might ask you something.
Ask away, dear boy, ask away.
The other day I was in the library,
in the Restricted Section...
...and I came across something rather odd
about a very rare piece of magic.
Yes. And what was this
rare piece of magic?
Well, I don't know.
I can't remember the name exactly.
It got me wondering, are there some kinds
of magic you're not allowed to teach us?
I'm Potions Master, Harry.
I think your question'd
better be posed to Professor Snape.
Yes. Um...
He and I don't exactly
see eye to eye, sir.
What I mean to say is...
...well, he's not like you.
He might misunderstand.
Yes. There can be no light
without the dark.
And so it is with magic. Myself, I always
strive to live within the light.
I suggest you do the same.
Is that what you told Tom Riddle,
when he came asking questions?
Dumbledore put you up to this,
didn't he?
Didn't he?
Yes?
Oh, it's you, Potter.
I'm sorry, I'm busy at the moment.
It's beautiful, isn't it? The moon.
Divine.
Had ourselves a little
late-night snack, did we?
It was on your bed, the box.
I just thought I'd try one.
- Or 20.
- I can't stop thinking about her, Harry.
Honestly, I reckoned
she was annoying you.
She could never annoy me.
I think I love her.
Well, brilliant.
Do you think she knows I exist?
I hope so. She's been snogging you
for three months.
Snogging? Who are you talking about?
Who are you talking about?
Romilda, of course. Romilda Vane.
Okay, very funny.
- What was that for?
- It's no joke! I'm in love with her!
Fine, you're in love with her.
Have you ever actually met her?
No. Can you introduce me?
Come on, Ron. I'm gonna introduce you
to Romilda Vane.
I'm sorry, sir. I wouldn't bother you
if it weren't absolutely essential.
Where's Romilda?
What's the matter with Wenby?
Very powerful love potion.
Very well. Better bring him in.
I'd have thought you could whip up
a remedy for this in no time, Harry.
Well, I thought this called
for a more practiced hand, sir.
Hello, darling. Fancy a drink?
Perhaps you're right.
I'm sorry, by the way, professor,
about earlier today, our misunderstanding.
Oh, not at all. All water
under the bridge, you know? Correct?
I expect you're tired of it
after all these years.
All the questions about Voldemort.
Don't use that name.
There you are, old boy. Bottoms up.
- What's this?
- Tonic for the nerves.
- What happened to me?
- Love potion.
A bloody strong one at that.
- I feel really bad.
- You need a pick-me-up.
Got Butterbeer,
wine, dazzling oak-matured mead.
I had other intentions for this,
but I think, given the circumstances...
Here we are, Potter.
To life!
Ron.
Ron. Professor, do something.
I don't understand.
Come on, Ron, breathe.
These girls, they're gonna kill me.
Quick thinking on your part, Harry,
using a bezoar.
You must be very proud
of your student, Horace.
Hm? Oh, yes, very proud.
I think we agree,
Potter's actions were heroic.
The question is,
why were they necessary?
Why, indeed?
This appears to be a gift, Horace.
You don't remember
who gave you this bottle?
Which, by the way, possesses remarkably
subtle hints of licorice and cherry...
...when not polluted with poison.
Actually I had intended
to give it as a gift myself.
To whom, I might ask?
To you, Headmaster.
Where is he?
Where's my Won-Won?
Has he been asking for me?
What's she doing here?
I might ask you the same question.
I happen to be his girlfriend.
I happen to be his friend.
Don't make me laugh.
You haven't spoken in weeks.
I suppose you want to make up
now that he's all interesting.
He's been poisoned, you daft dimbo!
And for the record,
I've always found him interesting.
Ah. See? He senses my presence.
Don't worry, Won-Won. I'm here.
I'm here.
Uh... Hermione...
Hermione.
Oh, to be young,
and to feel love's keen sting.
Well, come away, everybody.
Mr. Weasley is well tended.
About time, don't you think?
Thank you.
Oh, shut up.
Stop it, Ron. You're making it snow.
Tell me how I broke up
with Lavender again.
Um, well...
...she came to visit you
in the hospital.
And you talked.
I don't believe it was
a particularly long conversation.
Don't get me wrong, I'm bloody thrilled
to be shot of her.
It's just she seems a bit put out.
Yes, she does, doesn't she?
You say you don't remember
anything from that night?
Anything at all?
There is something.
But it can't be.
I was completely boggled, wasn't I?
Right. Boggled.
Harry.
That's Katie.
Katie Bell.
Katie. How are you?
I know you're going to ask, Harry,
but I don't know who cursed me.
I've been trying to remember, honestly.
But I just can't.
Katie?
I know what you did, Malfoy.
You hexed her, didn't you?
Sectumsempra!
Vulnera Sanentur.
You have to get rid of it. Today.
Take my hand.
The Room of Requirement.
We need to hide
the Half-Blood Prince's book...
...where no one will ever find it,
including you.
- What was that?
See?
You never know what you'll find up here.
All right, close your eyes.
That way you can't be tempted.
Close your eyes.
That can stay hidden up here too,
if you like.
So did you and Ginny do it, then?
What?
You know, hide the book?
Oh, yeah.
Ah. Dear, yes.
Still no luck with Slughorn, then,
I take it?
Luck.
That's it. All I need's a bit of luck.
Well, how do you feel?
Excellent.
Really excellent.
Remember...
...Slughorn usually eats early...
...takes a walk,
and then returns to his office.
Right.
- I'm going down to Hagrid's.
- What?
No, Harry, you've got to go
and speak to Slughorn.
- We have a plan.
- I know...
...but I've got a
good feeling about Hagrid's.
I feel it's the place to be tonight.
Do you know what I mean?
- No.
- Well, trust me, I know what I'm doing.
Or Felix does.
Hi!
Merlin's beard, Harry!
Sorry, sir. I should've announced myself.
Cleared my throat, coughed.
You probably feared
I was Professor Sprout.
Yes, I did, actually.
What makes you think that?
Well, just the general behavior, sir.
The sneaking around,
the jumping when you saw me.
Are those Tentacula leaves, sir?
They're very valuable, aren't they?
Ten Galleons a leaf to the right buyer.
Not that I'm familiar with any such
transactions, but one does hear rumors.
My own interests
are purely academic, of course.
Personally, these plants
always kind of freaked me out.
How did you get out of the castle, Harry?
Through the front door, sir.
I'm off to Hagrid's.
He's a very dear friend...
...and I fancied paying him a visit.
So if you don't mind,
I will be going now.
Harry!
- Sir?
- It's nearly nightfall.
Surely you realize I can't allow you
to go roaming the grounds by yourself.
Well, then, by all means, come along, sir.
Harry, I must insist
you accompany me...
...back to the castle immediately!
That would be counterproductive, sir.
And what makes you say that?
No idea.
Horace.
Merlin's beard.
Is that an actual Acromantula?
A dead one, I think, sir.
Good God.
Dear fellow,
however did you manage to kill it?
Kill it? Me oldest friend, he was.
- I'm so sorry, I didn't...
- Don't worry yourself, you're not alone.
Seriously misunderstood creatures,
spiders are.
It's the eyes, I reckon.
They unnerve some folk.
Not to mention the pincers.
Yeah, I reckon that too.
Hagrid, the last thing
I wish to be is indelicate...
...but Acromantular venom
is uncommonly rare.
Would you allow me
to extract a vial or two?
Purely for academic purposes,
you understand.
Well, I don't suppose it's going
to do him much good now, is it?
My thoughts exactly.
Always have a ampoule or two about
my person for just such occasions as this.
Old Potions Master's habit, you know.
I wish you could've seen him
in his prime.
Magnificent, he was. Just magnificent.
Oh, dear.
- Would you like me to say a few words?
- Yes.
He had a family, I trust?
Oh, yeah.
Farewell...
Aragog.
Farewell, Aragog...
...king of the arachnids.
Your body will decay...
...but your spirit lingers on.
And your human friends find solace
in the loss they have sustained.
I had him from an egg, you know.
Tiny little thing he was when he hatched.
No bigger than a Pekinese.
A Pekinese, mind you.
How sweet. I once had a fish. Francis.
He was very dear to me.
One afternoon I came downstairs,
and he'd vanished.
Poof.
- That's very odd, isn't it?
- It is, isn't it?
But that's life, I suppose.
You go along and then suddenly, poof!
- Poof.
It was a student who gave me Francis.
One spring afternoon
I discovered a bowl on my desk...
...with just a few inches
of clear water in it.
And floating on the surface
was a flower petal.
As I watched, it sank.
Just before it reached the bottom...
...it transformed...
...into a wee fish.
It was beautiful magic.
Wondrous to behold.
The flower petal had come from a lily.
Your mother.
The day I came downstairs...
...the day the bowl was empty...
...was the day your mother...
I know why you're here.
But I can't help you.
It would ruin me.
Do you know why I survived, professor?
The night I got this?
Because of her.
Because she sacrificed herself.
Because she refused to step aside.
Because her love was more powerful
than Voldemort.
- Don't say his name.
- I'm not afraid of the name, professor.
I'm going to tell you something.
Something others have only guessed at.
It's true.
I am the Chosen One.
Only I can destroy him,
but in order to do so...
...I need to know what Tom Riddle
asked you years ago in your office...
...and I need to know what you told him.
Be brave, professor.
Be brave like my mother.
Otherwise, you disgrace her.
Otherwise, she died for nothing.
Otherwise, the bowl
will remain empty forever.
Please, don't think badly of me
when you see it.
You've no idea what he was like,
even then.
I was in the library the other night...
...in the Restricted Section...
...and I read something rather odd
about a bit of rare magic.
It's called, as I understand it...
...a Horcrux.
- I beg your pardon?
- Horcrux.
I came across the term while reading...
...and I didn't fully understand it.
I'm not sure what you
were reading, Tom...
...but this is very dark stuff,
very dark indeed.
Which is...
...why I came to you.
A Horcrux is an object in which a person
has concealed part of their soul.
But I don't understand
how that works, sir.
One splits one's soul and hides
part of it in an object.
By doing so, you're protected, should
you be attacked and your body destroyed.
Protected?
That part of your soul
that is hidden lives on.
In other words, you cannot die.
And how does one split his soul, sir?
I think you already know
the answer to that, Tom.
Murder.
Yes.
Killing rips the soul apart.
It is a violation against nature.
Can you only split the soul
once? For instance, isn't seven...?
Seven?
Merlin's beard, Tom. Isn't it bad enough
to consider killing one person?
To rip the soul into seven pieces...
This is all hypothetical, isn't it, Tom?
All academic?
Of course, sir.
It'll be our little secret.
Sir.
This is beyond anything I imagined.
You mean to say he succeeded, sir,
in making a Horcrux?
Oh, yes, he succeeded, all right.
And not just once.
What are they exactly?
Could be anything.
Most commonplace of objects.
A ring, for example.
Or a book.
- Tom Riddle's diary.
- It's a Horcrux, yes.
Four years ago, when you saved
Ginny's life...
...in the Chamber of Secrets,
you brought me this.
I knew this was
a different kind of magic.
Very dark, very powerful. But until tonight
I had no idea just how powerful.
- The ring?
- Belonged to Voldemort's mother.
Difficult to find.
Even more difficult to destroy.
But if you could find them all,
if you did destroy each Horcrux...
One destroys Voldemort.
But how would you find them?
They could be hidden anywhere.
True. But magic, especially dark magic...
...leaves traces.
It's where you've been going,
isn't it, sir?
- When you leave the school?
- Yes.
And I think perhaps
I may have found another.
But this time,
I cannot hope to destroy it alone.
Once again,
I must ask too much of you, Harry.
Have you ever considered
that you ask too much...
...that you take too much for granted?
Has it ever crossed your brilliant mind
that I don't want to do this anymore?
Whether it has or hasn't is irrelevant.
I will not negotiate with you, Severus.
You agreed. Nothing more to discuss.
Oh, Harry.
You need a shave, my friend.
You know, at times,
I forget how much you've grown.
At times, I still see the small boy
from the cupboard.
Forgive my mawkishness, Harry.
I'm an old man.
You still look the same to me, sir.
Just like your mother,
you're unfailingly kind.
A trait people never fail to undervalue,
I'm afraid.
The place to which we journey tonight
is extremely dangerous.
I promised you could accompany me,
and I stand by that promise.
But there is one condition:
You must obey every command
I give you, without question.
Yes, sir.
You do understand what I'm saying?
Should I tell you to hide, you hide.
Should I tell you to run, you run.
Should I tell you to abandon me
and save yourself, you must do so.
Your word, Harry.
My word.
Take my arm.
Sir, I thought you couldn't
Apparate within Hogwarts.
Well, being me has its privileges.
This is the place.
Oh, yes.
This place has known magic.
- Sir!
- In order to gain passage...
...payment must be made.
Payment intended
to weaken any intruder.
- You should've let me, sir.
- No, Harry.
Your blood's much more precious
than mine.
Voldemort will not have made it easy
to discover his hiding place.
He will have put certain defenses
in position.
Careful.
There it is.
The only question is,
how do we get there?
If you would, Harry.
Do you think the Horcrux is in there, sir?
Oh, yes.
It has to be drunk.
All of it has to be drunk.
You remember the conditions on which
I brought you with me?
This potion might paralyze me.
Might make me forget why I'm here.
Might cause me so much pain
that I beg for relief.
You are not to indulge these requests.
It's your job, Harry, to make sure
I keep drinking this potion.
Even if you have to force it
down my throat.
- Understood?
- Why can't I drink it, sir?
Because I am much older, much cleverer,
and much less valuable.
Your good health, Harry.
Professor.
Professor!
Harry.
Professor, can you hear me?
Professor.
No. Don't.
You have to keep drinking,
like you said. Remember?
- Stop.
- It will stop. It will stop...
...but only if you keep drinking.
- Please, don't make me.
- I'm sorry, sir.
- Please.
- Kill me. Kill me!
- No!
It's my fault.
It's all my fault.
Just one more, sir.
One more, and then I promise...
...I promise I'll do what you say.
- I promise.
- No.
Please.
Harry.
Water.
You did it, sir.
Look.
Harry.
Water.
Aguamenti.
Lumos.
Lumos Maxima!
Harry.
Sectumsempra!
- Stupefy!
- Harry.
Harry.
Partis Temporus!
Go to your houses. No dawdling.
We need to get you to the hospital
wing, sir, to Madam Pomfrey.
No.
Severus. Severus is who I need.
Wake him. Tell him what happened.
Speak to no one else.
Severus, Harry.
Hide yourself below, Harry.
Don't speak or be seen by anybody
without my permission.
Whatever happens,
it's imperative you stay below.
Harry, do as I say.
Trust me.
Good evening, Draco.
What brings you here
on this fine spring evening?
Who else is here? I heard you talking.
I often talk aloud to
myself. I find it extraordinarily useful.
Have you been whispering
to yourself, Draco?
Draco...
...you are no assassin.
- How do you know what I am?
I've done things that would shock you.
Like cursing Katie Bell and hoping that in
return she'd bear a cursed necklace to me?
Replacing a bottle of mead
with one laced with poison?
Forgive me, Draco.
I cannot help feeling these actions
are so weak...
...your heart can't really
have been in them.
He trusts me. I was chosen.
Then I shall make it easy for you.
Expelliarmus!
Very good. Very good.
You're not alone.
There are others.
How?
The vanishing cabinet
in the Room of Requirement.
- I've been mending it.
- Let me guess.
It has a sister. A twin.
In Borgin and Burkes.
They form a passage.
Ingenious.
Draco...
...years ago, I knew a boy
who made all the wrong choices.
- Please let me help you.
- I don't want your help!
Don't you understand? I have to do this.
I have to kill you.
Or he's gonna kill me.
Well, look what we have here.
Well done, Draco.
Good evening, Bellatrix.
I think introductions
are in order, don't you?
Love to, Albus, but I'm afraid
we're all on a bit of a tight schedule.
Do it.
He doesn't have the stomach,
just like his father.
Let me finish him in my own way.
No! The Dark Lord was clear,
the boy is to do it.
This is your moment. Do it.
Go on, Draco.
Now!
No.
Severus.
Please.
Avada Kedavra.
Yeah!
Hagrid! Hello?
Snape! He trusted you!
Go on.
Incarcerous.
Fight back! You coward, fight back!
No! He belongs to the Dark Lord.
Sectumsempra!
You dare use my own spells
against me, Potter?
Yes.
I'm the Half-Blood Prince.
McGONAGALL:
Potter...
...in light of what has happened...
...if you should have the need
to talk to someone...
You should know,
Professor Dumbledore...
...you meant a great deal to him.
Do you think he would've done it?
Draco?
No.
No, he was lowering his wand.
In the end, it was Snape.
It was always Snape.
And I did nothing.
It's fake.
Open it.
"To the Dark Lord. I know I will be dead
long before you read this...
...but I want you to know that it was I
who discovered your secret.
I have stolen the real Horcrux and intend
to destroy it as soon as I can.
I face death in the hope that
when you meet your match...
...you will be mortal once more.
R.A.B."
R.A.B.
Don't know.
But whoever they are,
they have the real Horcrux.
Which means it was all a waste.
All of it.
Ron's okay with it, you know.
You and Ginny.
But if I were you, when he's around,
I'd keep the snogging to a minimum.
I'm not coming back, Hermione.
I've got to finish
whatever Dumbledore started.
And I don't know where that'll lead me...
...but I'll let you and Ron know
where I am when I can.
I've always admired your courage, Harry.
But sometimes, you can be really thick.
You don't really think
you're going to be able...
...to find all those Horcruxes
by yourself, do you?
You need us, Harry.
I never realized
how beautiful this place was.